<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="style/default.xsl"?>

<section>

  <section title="Build.jar" level="1">

    <p>Build.jar is a Java program that allows you to change project settings, test your visual novel, and create a packaged version for distribution.</p>
    
    <figure src="img/build-jar.png" alt="Screenshot of Build.jar" />
    
    <section title="Preferences" level="2">

      <p>There are several types of config/preference files that can be edited to customize your visual novel. <code>Build.jar</code> groups all these together into one big table with descriptions for each setting. It also has a basic/advanced mode toggle that hides less relevant settings.</p>
      
    </section>
    
    <section title="Build Commands" level="2">
      <section title="Rebuild" level="3">
        <p>(Re)creates the launcher scripts/executables required to test your visual novel. It's sometimes necessary to do a rebuild after changing files in <code>build-res</code> from outside Build.jar, or after updating NVList to a new version.</p>
        <p>If your Java installation is a JRE (Java runtime) and not a full JDK (Java devkit), the build system will give you the warning <code>unable to locate tools.jar</code>. It's safe to ignore this warning unless you're extending the engine itself with additional Java code (requires a JDK).</p>
      </section>
      <section title="Edit" level="3">
        <p>Opens the project script folder in a file browser.</p>
      </section>
      <section title="Backup" level="3">
        <p>Creates a backup copy of your script folder. The scripts are stored as <code>bak/script/script-$DATE.zip</code>.</p>
      </section>
      <section title="Run Game" level="3">
        <p>Starts NVList to test your visual novel.</p>
      </section>
      <section title="Resource Optimizer" level="3">    
        <p>Starts the resource optimizer. See: <a href="ch51-resource-optimizer.xml">Resource Optimizer</a></p>
      </section>
      <section title="Create Applet" level="3">
        <p>Creates an applet distribution for embedding into a webpage. See: <a href="ch50-create-distro.xml#create-applet">Creating a Distribution</a></p>
      </section>
      <section title="Create Release" level="3">
        <p>Packages your project and NVList files together ready for end-user distribution.  See: <a href="ch50-create-distro.xml#create-release">Creating a Distribution</a></p>
      </section>
      <section title="Create CD Release" level="3">
        <p>Creates a disk image (.iso) ready to burn onto a CD/DVD. See: <a href="ch50-create-distro.xml#create-cd-release">Creating a Distribution</a></p>
      </section>
      <section title="Create Android Project" level="3">
        <p>Opens the Android build config window for creating a port of your project to the <a href="http://www.android.com/">Android</a> operating system. See: <a href="ch52-android.xml">Releasing on Android</a></p>
      </section>
    </section>
      
  </section>
    
</section>
