<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="style/default.xsl"?>

<section>

  <section title="Folder Layout" level="1">

    <figure src="img/folders.png" alt="Install Folder" float="right">Install Folder</figure>

    <h4>Build.jar</h4>
    <p>Java program that provides a convenient graphical user interface for changing preferences and controlling the build system.</p>

    <h4>build.xml</h4>
    <p>Apache <a href="http://ant.apache.org/">ant</a> build script. Can be called from the command line, or by using the &quot;build command&quot; buttons in Build.jar.</p>

    <h4>license.txt</h4>
    <p>NVList software license. It contains the same text that gets shown in info-&gt;about menu item at runtime.</p>

    <h4>README.html</h4>
    <p>Forwards to this manual.</p>
    
    <section title="build-res" level="2">
      <figure src="img/folders-build-res.png" alt="/build-res" float="right">build-res</figure>
      
      <h4>applet</h4>
      <p>Contains the template files used for generating applet distributions.</p>
      
      <h4>extra-dist-files</h4>
      <p>All files contained in this folder are copies to the root folder of distributions.</p>
      
      <h4>launcher</h4>
      <p>Contains templates for launcher scripts.</p>
      
      <h4>mac</h4>
      <p>Contains resources for the Mac OS X distribution.</p>
      
      <h4>android-config.ini</h4>
      <p>Stores the settings for the Android build config. These can be changed using Build.jar.</p>
      
      <h4>build.properties</h4>
      <p>Stores settings related to the build system. These can be changed using Build.jar.</p>
      
      <h4>build-android.xml, build-applet.xml, build-game.xml, build-distro.xml</h4>
      <p>Apache <a href="http://ant.apache.org/">ant</a> build scripts used by build.xml in the engine root folder.</p>
      
      <h4>installer.manifest</h4>
      <p>Used by the .exe version of installers generated by Build.jar to defeat the 'intelligent' installer detection in Windows Vista onwards which makes it impossible to run an executable with 'install' in its name without administrator priviliges.</p>
      
      <h4>installer-config.ini</h4>
      <p>Stores settings related to installer creation. They can be changed using Build.jar.</p>
      
      <h4>splash.png</h4>
      <p>Splash screen image used by the installer.</p>
      
      <h4>splash-android.png</h4>
      <p>Splash screen image used by the Android port during startup.</p>
    </section>

    <section title="documentation" level="2">
      <p>Contains this manual, generated function references and source code for the built-in Lua scripts.</p>
    </section>

    <section title="lib" level="2">
      <p>The lib folder contains all the different libraries that make up NVList.</p>
    </section>

    <section title="res" level="2">
      <figure src="img/folders-res.png" alt="/res" float="right">res</figure>

      <h4>font</h4>
      <p>All fonts used by the VN should be stored in the font folder. Fonts should be in TrueType (.ttf) format.</p>

      <h4>img</h4>
      <p>Stores all image files, refer to the <a href="ch11-resources.xml#images">resources chapter</a> for more information.</p>

      <h4>script</h4>
      <p>Script files (.lua, .lvn) are stored in here.</p>

      <h4>shader</h4>
      <p>Stores <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Glsl">GLSL shaders</a>. The type of shader is determined by the file extension. Use .vert for vertex shaders, and .frag for fragment shaders.</p>
      
      <h4>snd</h4>
      <p>Stores all audio files, refer to the <a href="ch11-resources.xml#audio">resources chapter</a> for more information.</p>

      <h4>video</h4>
      <p>Stores all video files, refer to the <a href="ch11-resources.xml#video">resources chapter</a> for more information.</p>

      <h4>game.ini</h4>
      <p>Stores settings that may not be overridden by the end-user such as the game title and screen size.</p>

      <h4>icon.icns, icon.ico, icon.png</h4>
      <p>The icon used for the main window (.png), Windows executable (.ico) and Mac application bundle (.icns). You can use a site like <a href="http://iconverticons.com/">iconverticons.com</a> to generate the .ico/.icns files.</p>

      <h4>keyconfig.ini</h4>
      <p>Maps keyboard and gamepad buttons to virtual controls used by the engine internally.</p>

      <h4>prefs-default.ini</h4>
      <p>Stores settings just like game.ini, but the settings in prefs-default.ini may be changed by the user.</p>
      
    </section>
    
    <section title="src" level="2">
      <p>Folder optionally containing .java source files to compile into the final program.</p>
    </section>
    
    <section title="tools" level="2">
      <p>Contains tools and plugins used by the build system during development. When creating a distribution, these files aren't included.</p>
    </section>

  </section>
  
</section>
