<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="style/default.xsl"?>

<section>

  <section title="Pre-Distribution Checklist" level="1">

    <section title="Turn Off Debug Mode" level="3">
      <p>Turn off <code>debug</code> in <code>Build.jar</code> or manually set <code>debug</code> to false in <code>res/prefs-default.ini</code>.</p>
    </section>

    <section title="Proofreader Tools" level="3">
      <p>The proofreader tools (activated through <code>vn.enableProofreaderTools</code>) provide a convenient shortcut in the menu bar for proofreaders to report bugs or typos. Don't forget to turn it off before the final release.</p>
    </section>

    <section title="Check Customizations" level="3">
      <p>Make sure you've customized everything you want:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Settings: <code>project-name</code> and <code>title</code></li>
        <li>The application icon: <code>res/icon.icns</code>, <code>res/icon.ico</code> and <code>res/icon.png</code></li>
        <li>The installer splash screen image: <code>build-res/splash.png</code></li>
        <li>When creating an Android port: <code>build-res/splash-android.png</code></li>
        <li>When creating an applet release: <code>build-res/applet/header.jpg</code> and <code>build-res/applet/splash.jpg</code></li>
      </ul>
    </section>

    <section title="Test Generated Release" level="3">
      <p>After creating the release with <code>Build.jar</code>, test it on a variety of computers (preferably with different operating systems).</p>
    </section>
    
  </section>

  <section title="Creating a Distribution" level="1">

    <p><code>Build.jar</code> can be used to create a release (Regular, CD, Android or Applet). The release options are under the &quot;...&quot; button above the &quot;Run Game&quot; button.</p>
    
    <figure src="img/build-jar.png" alt="Screenshot of Build.jar" />
    
    <section title="Create Release" id="create-release" level="3">
      <p>Packages your project and NVList files together ready for end-user distribution. The generated files are created in the <code>releases</code> folder. Four files are created by default:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>A Windows-only .exe installer (sends user to java.com if no Java installed)</li>
        <li>A zipped application bundle for Mac OSX</li>
        <li>A cross-platform no-installer zip file</li>
        <li>A cross-platform self-extracting JAR installer</li>
      </ul>
    </section>
    <section title="Create CD Release" id="create-cd-release" level="3">
      <p>Creates a disk image (.iso) ready to burn onto a CD/DVD. Added to the CD are the Mac OS X application bundle, the no-installer .zip and a Windows-only .exe installer.</p>
    </section>
    <section title="Create Applet" id="create-applet" level="3">
      <p>Creates an applet distribution for embedding into a webpage. The applet is created in <code>dist</code>. Warning: users will be given a threatening looking security popup when first running the applet.</p>
    </section>    
    <section title="Create Android Release" id="create-android-release" level="3">
      <p>Opens the Android Build Config window, see the chapter on <a href="ch52-android.xml">Android distributions</a> for more details.</p>
    </section>    
    
    <section title="Distribution Settings" level="2">
      <section title="Obfuscation" level="3">
        <p>The <code>obfuscate</code> preference determines if resources included in the distribution should be made harder to access by curious end-users. When obfuscation is turned off, resources are distributed in a regular <code>res.zip</code> file as opposed to a non-standard <code>.nvl</code> file when obfuscation is turned on.</p>
      </section>
      <section title="Adding Files to a Distribution" level="3">
        <p>All resources must be stored in the <code>res</code> folder. These files will be packed into a single <code>.nvl</code> file upon distribution. To add end user readable files to a distribution, place them in the <code>build-res/extra-dist-files</code> folder. Any files/folders stored there will be included in distributions in the game root folder as regular files.</p>
      </section>
    </section>
    
  </section>
  
</section>
