<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="style/default.xsl"?>

<section>

  <section title="Resource Optimizer" level="1">
    
    <p>The resource optimizer can convert/optimize all images, audio and video in a project at once. You're automatically asked (if necessary) to run the resource optimizer by <code>Build.jar</code> prior to creating a release. The result of the resource optimizer is a folder named <code>res-optimized</code> which is automatically used instead of the regular <code>res</code> folder for creating releases (after the build system checks it's up-to-date).</p>
    
    <p><strong>You need an <a href="http://ffmpeg.org/">FFmpeg</a> <a href="http://ffmpeg.zeranoe.com/builds/">executable</a> either in the tools folder, or in your <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PATH_%28variable%29">PATH</a> to do audio/video optimization.</strong></p>
     
    <p><a href="http://pmt.sourceforge.net/pngcrush/">pngcrush</a> will be used if made available in the same way (it further compresses PNG images by a few percent).</p>

  </section>
  
  <figure src="img/resource-optimizer.png" alt="Resource Optimizer" />
  
  <section title="Resource Optimizer Settings" level="2">
  
    <section title="Target Resolutions" level="3">
      <p>A comma-separated list of target resolutions (<code>width</code>x<code>height</code>) to pre-scale the images for. Use <code>original</code> if you want to include an unscaled version. The optimizer will never change the aspect ratio, so if you for example add <code>1024x600</code> and your images are 16:9, the generated images will be <code>1024x576</code> instead.</p>
    </section>

    <section title="Image Format Preset" level="3">
      <p>The selected image format preset determines the file formats that will be considered for optimized images. The &quot;Default&quot; value is conservative, generating only JPEG and PNG files. The other presets may generate images in the more obscure JNG/KTX formats where appropriate. Some presets may not be available when optimizing for an Android release.</p>
    </section>
    
    <section title="Image Quality" level="3">
      <p>Sets the quality for lossy (JPEG) image compression between <code>0.0</code> and <code>1.0</code>. If you check the &quot;Scale with resolution&quot; box, the quality you specify will be increased slightly when downscaling (since errors are more visible at lower resolutions).</p>
    </section>
    
    <section title="Lossless Only Folders" level="3">
      <p>A comma separated list of file patterns that should never use lossy image compression.</p>
    </section>
    
    <section title="Audio Quality" level="3">
      <p>The value to pass to FFmpeg's -aq parameter.</p>
    </section>

    <section title="Video Format" level="3">
      <p>The video format extension and bitrate to use for video.</p>
    </section>
    
  </section>
  
</section>